Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and share this video as much as possible.
Before looking at the big news,
today's question for you is which country is called the land of white elephants
?  Option A India, Option
B Thailand, Option C Sri Lanka, Option D
Kenya.  Answer this question by commenting
and tell us which state and city's news do you
want to see more?  Tell us by commenting
so that we can show more news of your state or city.
Let us now see today's quick
big news.   The
Supreme Court said that the paper was never leaked in UPSC.
NTA needs to learn from them.
These incidents will not stop until accountability is fixed.  The
Supreme Court
said on the NEET UG paper leak case that
such incidents will not stop until accountability is fixed.   The
National Testing Agency (NTA) present in the court was
asked that UPSC
conducts examinations on a larger scale than you.   The
paper was never leaked there.  NTA
needs to learn from them.
Solicitor General Tushar Mehta, on behalf of the government, said that
Prime Minister Narendra Modi himself is
monitoring the investigation into the NEET paper leak so that
no mistake is made.  Justice
Narasimha, who was hearing the case, sought details from the Education Ministry on the
scrutiny of the process of NEET UG examinations
and the Solicitor General informed that
major improvements have been made after the paper leak.
Solicitor General Tushar Mehta
also said that we are serious about the youth
and NEET UG is adopting new methods for re-test.   The
High Court should not reserve its decision for more than 3 months.
Supreme Court
directs to pass order on bail on the same day or the next
day.  Upload immediately.  The Supreme Court has
expressed concern over the delay in decisions in all the High Courts across the country.  The court said
that after reserving the decision in any case,
it should be pronounced within 3 months.
If the decision is not given within 3 months, then the
Registrar General of the High Court will
place the matter before the Chief Justice.  The bench headed by CJI Surya Kant
also said that the order on the bail pleas should be
pronounced on the same day.  If the decision is
reserved, it
must be issued the next day and uploaded on the website immediately.   There can be
four Deputy CMs in Karnataka.
Shiv Kumar will be sworn in as CM, possibly next week.
Siddha Ramaiah met Rahul and Kharge.
Siddaramaiah reached Delhi just a day after resigning from the post of Chief Minister in Karnataka.
Here he
met Congress leader Rahul Gandhi and party president Mallikarjun Kharge.
According to media reports, in this meeting
Siddharth Ramaiah has placed many of his demands before the high command.  In
which the demand for an
important ministry in the new cabinet for his son Yendra Siddar Ramaiah is
also said to be included.  On
the other hand, the resignation of Karnataka Chief Minister
Siddaramaiah has been accepted.
According to news agency ANI, party
sources have said that DK may take oath along with the new ministers next week.
Four deputy CMs can also be appointed to maintain social and regional balance in the government.
NEET re-test paper
will reach the exam centre with the help of Army and Air Force.  The deadline for piece refunds was
also extended.  The
decision was taken in the meeting held at Rajnath Singh's house.  Amid the NEET UG
paper leak controversy, a high-level meeting was held with
Defence Minister Rajnath Singh ahead of the re-test to be held on June 21.
Union Education Minister Dharmendra
Pradhan, Union Minister Jyotiraditya
Scindia, National Testing Agency NDA
Director General Abhishek Singh participated in it and
Pradhan has
sought the help of Army and Air Force for NEET paper like UPSC.   The
Defence Ministry has agreed to this.   It was
decided in the meeting that now the entire work from setting the paper,
printing, transportation to
delivering the paper to the examination centre will be
monitored at many levels.
Ban on sale of Absolute Bodhga Shivas Regal in Delhi continues.  Pernod
evaded taxes of ₹3000 crore on record.  The
license was cancelled following ED allegations.  The ban on the sale of liquor
like Absolute Bodga and Sivas Regal remains in place in Delhi.   The
Delhi High Court has dismissed a plea by French liquor giant
Pernod Ricard
seeking permission to sell its products in Delhi.   The
company is out of the Delhi market since 2023
due to being accused in the Delhi Liquor Policy 2021 investigation.
Delhi authorities have rejected the
liquor licence application for Parnod Records
and the reason for this is the serious
allegations made by the Enforcement Directorate (ED).
In which it is said that
in the year 2021, the company had colluded with
retailers i.e. liquor sellers to illegally increase its market share.
New York Mayor Mamdani opposed the Iran war.
Said thousands of lives were lost in this.  People are
paying the price for a careless decision.
New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani has
opposed the Iran war.  He said
that this war should end now
because the common people are paying the biggest price for it today.
Posting on social media platform X, Mamdani said that
three months ago a war started
for which no one had voted.
But the price was paid by those who had no
voice in it.  He said that
thousands of civilians have lost their lives in this war.  Along with this,
13 American soldiers were
also killed who will never be able to return to their families.
In the Twisha case, the mother-in-law and husband will be interrogated
face to face on 5-day CBI remand.  A
virtual recreation of the actress's last hours will be done.
In the case of actress and model Twister Sharma, the CBI
produced her mother-in-law, retired judge Giribala Singh, and husband Samarth Singh before a special court
and the investigating agency has
sought a remand of two to five days.  The court has
approved the remand.  The lawyer of the accused party
also did not oppose the demand for remand.
Samarth Singh was already on 7-day CBI
remand and after the remand ended,
he was again produced in the court.
Both the accused were present in the courtroom from 12:34 pm to 2:08 pm.
After which the CBI team
took him with them and left.
Netanya's order to occupy 70% of Gaza,
people said take 100% control.
Israeli PM said it will be done gradually.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Nyayahu has
ordered the military to take control of 70% of the Gaza Strip.  "We are currently suppressing Hamas," he said
during a press conference in the West Bank.
Now we control 60% of the Gaza Strip
and earlier we were at 50 and
then reached 60.  I ordered that by
increasing it.  Then someone from the crowd shouted
100%.  On this, Natan Yau said let us move forward one step at a time.  The
first reach 70%.
For now, let's start from there.  If we are
pressuring them from all sides and will
deal with the remaining ones as well.
Wrestler Vinesh Phogat will be able to give trials for the Asian Games.  The Supreme Court
granted permission.  He said, you are a great wrestler but the country comes first. The
Supreme Court has given permission to Haryana's
Olympic wrestler Vinesh Phogat for the
trials of the Asian Games.  On May 28, the
Wrestling Federation of India (WFI) had
filed a petition in the Supreme Court to stop Phogat's trial.  Which was rejected by the
bench of Justice PS Narasimha and Justice Alok Arage.
These trials are to be held in Delhi on 30th and 31st May.
Based on the performance in these trials, players will be selected for the Asian Games to be held in Japan in September this year.  The
Delhi High Court,
in its order dated May 22, had allowed Vinesh Phogat to
participate in the selection trials
and the same decision was challenged by the WFI
in the Supreme Court.
Preparations to change the 10-year-old rule of featuring Trump on the $250 note in the US.  Parliament's approval is pending.
Preparations have begun in America to issue a $250 note with Donald Trump's picture.   The
Trump government says that if Congress
changes the law, the
way for printing new notes will be cleared.  US
Treasury Secretary Scott Besson said that there is
a rule in America
under which the picture of any living person
cannot be printed on the note and efforts are being made to change this rule.
If the proposal is passed,
Trump will be the first living person to appear on a US note in more than 150 years.
Rajasthan tourist fined ₹7500 in Himachal.  They were
doing stunts on the roof of a burning car.
Argued with Manali Police.
In the tourist town of Manali in Himachal Pradesh,
hooliganism and stunts by tourists from Rajasthan proved
costly.  Actually,
Manali Police has
issued a challan of ₹7500 for the tourist's vehicle under the Motor Vehicle Act
and has warned him not to do so in future.
Actually, 4 to 5 tourists were
returning from Rohtang to Manali in the afternoon.
During this time some tourists were sitting on the roof of the vehicle.
Then he was managing the traffic near Bhootnath bridge in Manali.
Police station in-charge
Manali Manish Raj stopped them and
asked for documents.  During this time, tourists who had come to visit
also got into a scuffle with the police and locals.  The
atmosphere became tense for some time and the police
calmed everyone down.  After this, the police
checked the driver and the vehicle documents
after which a fine was imposed.
Punjab civic election results: Congress wins in Kapurthala
, BJP in Abohar,
Aam Aadmi Party wins in Moga and Barnala.  CM said,
Bengal is at fifth position to win.  Aam Aadmi Party has dominated the elections of
eight municipal corporations, 75 municipal councils and
20 nagar panchayats in Punjab.
In the counting of votes which is going on since 8:00 am, Aam
Aadmi Party has won in 881 wards.  Congress is at second place
and independent candidate is at third place.   The
BJP, which is talking about winning Punjab in 2027 after Bengal,
is lagging behind.  Akali Dal, which is claiming a comeback,
is also at number four.  However, Congress has
shown dominance in Kapurthala Municipal Corporation and has
gained majority.  Congress has won 31 out of 50 wards.
BJP has got majority in Abohar Municipal Corporation and the
party has won 28 seats here.
Whereas Aam Aadmi Party has won in Moga Corporation and Barnala Corporation.   The
Supreme Court said that you call those from whom you take money
beggars.  In the dowry case, he said
stop insulting the daughter-in-law and her family.
Brother-in-law's sentence upheld.  The Supreme Court has made strong remarks
during the hearing of a case related to this torture.   The
bench of Justice BB Nagarathna and Justice Ujjal Bhaya said that the
insult of the daughter-in-law and her family by the boy and his family should be
stopped.  The court said that a
message should be sent that insult to the daughter-in-law and her family will
not be tolerated.
Monsoon will now reach Kerala after 7 days.
Stormy winds stopped in Sri Lanka.  10%
less rainfall expected.  Heat wave will continue in June and July also.  The
entry of monsoon in the country has been delayed.  The
Meteorological Department has said that
due to low pressure storm winds over Sri Lanka, the monsoon has moved 3035 km away from the Kerala coast.  It has been
stuck for the last 5 days and there is
no possibility of it moving forward in the next two-three days.  The
normal date for the monsoon to reach the Kerala coast is June 1, and
earlier, the Meteorological Department had predicted the monsoon to arrive only by May 26.
According to the latest forecast, it will now reach the coast of Kerala after 7 days.  That
means
monsoon will enter the country about 10 days after the previous estimate.
According to IMD, heat wave is likely to continue in Uttar
Pradesh, Haryana, Punjab, Bihar, Odisha,
Chhattisgarh, Gujarat and Andhra Pradesh in June-July also.
Usually the
temperature at that time remains around 30-35° and this side the
temperature will be 3° higher.
Rahul Gandhi ate food with auto drivers and
wore uniform.  We sat on the ground in the park and
talked for half an hour.  Said he will
raise the issue in Parliament.  Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha
Rahul Gandhi reached among
auto rickshaw drivers at Todarmal Park in Bengali Market, Delhi.
Where
he talked to auto drivers.  Rahul was
also seen wearing his uniform and
some videos of Rahul Gandhi sitting in the park have surfaced.
In which he is
seen eating food with auto drivers.  During this time he was
also seen riding an auto.  Rahul Gandhi
spoke to auto drivers about their daily challenges, their income, rising expenses and working conditions.  Listened to their complaints
and discussed their lifestyle and problems.   The
ex-account of Cockroach Janata Party will remain
closed for now.  Delhi High Court
refuses to lift the ban.  Asked the government and X to
respond within four weeks.  The Delhi High Court has
issued notice to the Central Government and X on the petition of Cockroach Janata Party founder Abhijeet Dipke.  Deepak has
challenged the blocking of CJP's ex-account.  The
court currently
refused to give an interim order to reopen the account.  The
court said that
before taking a decision in this matter, it is necessary to hear the government's side.  The
bench of Justice Purushendra Kumar Kaur said that
such an order cannot be given without hearing the government's side because the
case has wide-ranging implications and far-reaching consequences.  The
court has asked the central government to
file its reply within four weeks and has
fixed the next hearing of the case on July 6.
Heavy rains in Bihar, darkness during the day in 20 districts,
seven people
died due to lightning.  100 km/h storm in UP.
Storm and rain alert has been
issued in Bihar.  Darkness descended early in the morning in districts including Patna, Khagaria, Rohtas,
Aurangabad, Kaimur, Chapra.
Then it rained heavily.
Seven people have lost their lives due to lightning in the state.
Due to dark clouds,
people were seen travelling with their vehicle lights on
and according to the Meteorological Department, the
weather will remain the same in Bihar for the next three days.
Meanwhile, heat wave conditions will prevail during the day in Gwalior, Morena,
Shivpur, Niwari, Tikamgarh and Chhatarpur districts of Madhya Pradesh.
Whereas in the evening
hail may fall along with rain.
Instead of heat, the series of storms and rains continues in Uttar Pradesh.  There was
rain accompanied by strong storm in Lucknow, Prayagraj, Jhansi and Chandauli.  100
km  Winds blew at a speed of per hour.
Today's good thought is written in Bhagavad Gita.  A
person can become as great as
he can think.  Do let us know how you liked this video
in the comment section.  If you
like the video then please like and share the video
and to watch such [Music] interesting videos
subscribe to our channel Jio News and press the bell icon and
do check our playlist and community tab to watch our old and latest videos.  So see you in the next video.
Thank you for now.  [music]